让我们进入 Dockerfile 的简介，所以，到目前为止，我们所关注的一切
Let's get into intro to Dockerfiles, so,
so far everything that we've been focused
关于 Docker 已在运行现有容器，是吗 ?
on with regards to Docker has been on
running existing containers, right?
对于工程师和其他工程师来说
Which again, for engineers and
开发商，大概是你用容器做的，对吧 ?
developers, it's probably most of what
you'll be doing with containers, right?
但我也认为，了解如何构建容器是有用的，
But it's also I think,
useful to know how to build containers,
有很多种不同的方法
there's a bunch of
different ways to do it.
让我们称之为最常见的
Let's call it the most common and
我认为最好的方法是使用 Dockerfile。
my opinion best way of doing
it is with Dockerfiles.
就像一个叫 Dockerfile 的文件格式
So there's actually like a file
format called Dockerfile and
Docker 会进行此操作，然后使用该方法为您构建容器。
Docker reads this and then it uses
that to build containers for you.
所以，让我们直接跳到其中，开始构建一些东西，好吗 ?
So let's just jump right into it and
start building something, all right?
所以在你的电脑上我要去做个私人的
So somewhere on your computer I'm gonna
go into, let's go into personal, and
我要制作一个叫 " to -to - containers " 的目录好吗
I'm gonna make a directory called
intro-to-containers, okay?
我要把目录改为 " 去容器"
I'm gonna change directory
into intro-to-containers,
我要把我的 VS 码打开到容器里
I'm going to open my VS code
into intro-to-containers.
所以现在我有了
So right now I have
只是一个空的目录我们要开始做一些项目
just an empty directory that we're gonna
start making some projects together,
再一次我创造了一个 GitHub 存储库
and again, there is a GitHub repo
out there that I've created.
GitHub btholt 项目
GitHub btholt projects for
完成了对容器的处理
complete intro-to-containers,
这个存在，这个有我要做的所有档案，
this exists out there, this has all
of the files that I'm about to do, it
也就像逃学群一样，像一个空壳档案一样。
also has like the truancy groups and all
those like it has those as a shell file.
举个例子，我们将要做的是 Dockerfile ，你可以想象，
So for example, we're about to do
Dockerfiles, so as you may imagine,
有一个叫 Dockerfile 的目录，单击它。
there's a directory called Dockerfile,
click on that.
在那里有一个 Docker 文件，对吧 ?
And on behold there's a Docker
file in there, right?
所以如果你落后了或者你不喜欢打字
So if you get behind or
if you don't feel like typing them or
之类的东西都在那儿
something like that, it's all there, and
我试着让它变得很明显是什么地方，对吧 ?
I try to make it pretty self
evident what goes where, right?
所以如果我要到 Dockerfile 的简介里，对吧 ?
So if I go here into intro to Dockerfiles,
right?
这是 Dockerfile ，我尝试这样称呼它
This is Dockerfile,
I try to call it the same thing so
如果你在这里也叫 Dockerfile
that if you go over here
it's also called Dockerfile.
再次，我将再次使用 Visual Studio 代码，因此
So again, I'm gonna be using Visual Studio
code, again, I work on it, so
我喜欢，我也觉得是一个很棒的编辑，所以
I like it, I also think it's
a really great editor, so
你一定要用它但是你也不用
you should definitely use it but
you also don't have to.
我会很悲伤的所以我要把所有项目都留在这里
I will just be very sad, so, I'm just
gonna make all my projects in here,
我要把一个叫 dockerfile 的目录， cd 到 dockerfile。
I'm gonna make a directory called
dockerfile, cd into dockerfile.
现在我们有了一个目录 Instro-to-Containers ，
And here, now that we have a directory,
Intro-to-Containers,
你可以看到我有一个 dockerfile 目录在这里创建一个新的文件
so you can see here I have a dockerfile
directory, create a new file in here and
它会被称为 Dockerfile
it's gonna be called Dockerfile.
我在那儿得到了一个很好的东西，所以我们有一个 Dockerfile ，对吧 ?
And I get a nice little, well right there,
so we have a Dockerfile, right?
所以我们要在这里创建一个文件， Docker
So what we're going to create here is
we're going to create a file that Docker
将会被读出来，它会用这个来为我们建造一个容器，对吧 ?
is going to read, and it's going to use
that to build a container for us, right?
所以这是一系列的指令，对吧 ?
So it's a series of instructions, right?
做这个，然后做这个，然后做这个，
Do this, then do this,
then do this, then do this,
那是非常程序性的
it's very procedural in
that particular way.
每一条线都被称为指令，对吗 ?
And literally each line is
called an instruction, right?
这就是为什么我说，使用指令，因为这就是它的字面意义。
That's why I say, use instructions,
because that's literally what it is,
所以我们要像最基本的节点 Dockerfile 一样
so we're gonna make like the most
basic node, Dockerfile ever.
所以你首先需要的是一个基本的容器，所以你说，
So, the first thing you need to start out
with is a base container, so you say,
FROM，我的自动完成很棒，感谢 VS 码，在后面拍我自己。
FROM, I get nice auto-completion,
thanks VS code, pat myself on the back.
我没这么做所以我不知道我为什么要这么做 FROM
I didn't do it so
I don't know why I'm doing that, FROM,
然后开始使用某个基本级别的容器。
and then you start with
some base level container.
所以我们要从已经开始使用的其中一个开始
So we're gonna start with one of them
that we've already been using, so
我要说的是 FROM 节点:12 伸展
I'm gonna say, FROM node:12-stretch So
它知道要去 Docker Hub 会发现
it knows it's gonna go out to Docker Hub,
it's gonna find
我们的节点拉伸容器，它是这个的起点，对吧 ?
our node stretch container, and that
is the starting point for this, right?
所以我们知道这个是有节点的，
So we know that this has
node installed in it,
我们知道在它上安装了 npm
we know that it has npm installed on it.
我们知道它有一些其他的特点
We know that it has some other
features like they've already created
一个节点用户那里有一堆东西对吧
a node user for us there's
a bunch of stuff in there, right?
我想说如果你在做一个节点
Bunch of goodness I'm going to
suggest like if you're doing a node
容器，对吧 ?
container, right?
就像一个节点项目，从这样的东西开始，对吧 ?
Like a node project,
start with something like this, right?
不一定是这个，外面有其他的，
It doesn't necessarily have to be this
one, there are other ones out there,
我想， " 节点源 " 发出了一个。
I think, Node Source makes one.
有一家公司的名字是我的名字
There's another company that I'm
just blanking on the name but
有一堆能制造好容器的
there's a bunch of them that
make really good containers.
好吧那接下来的事
Okay, and then the next thing in here,
我只是想让它在它开始的时候做点事情对吧
I'm just gonna tell it to do something
whenever it starts up, right?
我要说的是 CMD 然后你告诉它当它启动时要做什么
So I'm gonna say, CMD, and then you tell
it what to do when it starts up, and
你给了它一系列的东西对吧
you give it an array of things, right?
所以在这个例子中，我要说，节点，我们希望它运行节点，
So in this case, I'm gonna say,
node, we want it to run node,
那我们就给它带 -e 的旗帜
then we're gonna give it the flag of -e.
现在我们要说，运行 console.log，我们必须逃离这些。
And now we're gonna say, run console.log,
we have to escape these.
好了好了
There we go.
因此 -e 就意味着立即执行此处的代码字符串，因此
So -e just means immediately execute
this string of code right here, so
它实际上是把它喂给它就像节点要运行的文件一样
it's actually feeding this in as if it was
like the file that node's gonna run for
你对吧
you, right?
就像你想象的一样这只是打个招呼
So as you might imagine,
this is just gonna run hi.
所以我要告诉你如果我说的是节点 -e
So, just to show you, if I say node -e,
那我就在这儿
Then I do that here.
但愿那是意外的事对吧
Hopefully that's unsurprising what
that was supposed to do, right?
这就是 -e 的意思吧
That's what the -e does, right?
就是想给你看，因为大多数人可能不执行代码
Just wanted to show you that, because most
people probably don't execute their code
那样的话我就看不出原因了
that way, and I can't see why not.
我只是开个玩笑这主意糟透了别这么做
I'm just kidding, it's a terrible idea,
don't do that [LAUGH]
好吧那就这样吧
all right, so that's it, right?
这可能是您可以在其中写入的最基本节点应用程序
This is probably the most basic
node application you could write in
dockerfile 。
a dockerfile.
如果你还记得
Now, if you remember,
如果你直接运行节点，它就会掉到波纹中，对吗 ?
if you just run node stretch directly,
it just drops into the ripple, right?
所以它在那里有自己的 CMD 所以这就是 CMD 的运作方式
So it has its own CMD in there,
so that's how CMD works,
就能找到它的最后一个对吧
it takes the last one that it found,
right?
这是它找到的最后一个 CMD
So this is the last CMD that it finds so
它执行这个，上面写过那个，是吧 ?
it executes this one, it overwrote
the one that was previously there, right?
所以如果我在下面有一个说我不知道
So if I have one underneath
here that says, I don't know,
啊，对，最后一个，
right, it will do this last one,
现在对密码说你在这里有两次 CMD
now, vs codes gonna say,
you have CMD in here twice.
为甚么呢 ? 你为什么要这么对你自己
Why?
Why would you do that to yourself?
对吧 ? 所以感谢 VS 码，但是
Right?
So thanks VS code, but
我们就把这条线弄走我们就这样做
we'll just get rid of that line and
we'll do it like this,
好了我要把我的 CRI 打开
all right, so I'm gonna open my CRI here.
我是说这个特殊的文件我会说码头的建造
And I mean this particular file,
and I'm gonna say docker build,
告诉我码头档案在哪里
and just tell where the docker file is,
如果您需要 dockerfile ，那么您可以告诉它其他内容 ( 如果需要 ) 。
as soon as you need the dockerfile you can
tell it something else if you need to.
让我说在这里建个码头对吧
Let me say docker build.,
dot mean right here, right?
在此目录中查找 Docker 文件。
And look for
the Docker file in this directory.
好吧所以它会说从节点 12 号开始
Okay, so
it's gonna say FROM node:12-stretch,
我们大多数人可能还在我们的电脑上对吧
most of us probably still have
that on our computer, right?
所以它马上就会
So it'll immediately do that,
然后再在上面建立一层这就是我们所做的
and then it builds another layer on top of
that, which is this command that we do and
然后在这里用这个名字建造了这个集装箱
then it built this container
right here with this name.
所以我要说 Docker 经营或者我们不知道
So I'm gonna say docker run-it,
or actually we don't
甚至还得这么做你可以说 Docker 会运行它
even have to do the it,
you can say docker run that.
然后我们就开始了第一个我们创造的容器。
And there you go, we just ran our
first container that we've created.
我觉得这对大家都很重要
And I feel like this was really
important for everyone to see, probably
最好的容器绝对是最好的容器
the best container ever, definitely
the best container ever, all right.
你感觉怎么样
How do you feel about that?
有道理吗
Makes sense?
到目前为止还好吗
Good so far?
太酷了
Cool.
>> CMG 是九，零，不需要文档文件，但它是有用的东西，
&gt;&gt; CMG is nine, zero, it's not required
for dockerfile, but it's a useful thing,
否则，它将会发生任何缺省情况。
otherwise, it's going
to default to whatever.
>> ，前面的是什么，对吧 ?
&gt;&gt; Whatever the previous from is, right?
你可以做的容器是设计来执行的，对吗 ?
And you can make containers that are like
are designed to have execute, right?
Cuz ，我还能做 Docker ，我可以做 LS，对吧 ?
Cuz I can still do Docker run this and
I can do LS, right?
它会覆盖那里，那是 CMD ，对吧 ?
And it'll overwrite that,
that's CMD in there, right?
这些都是在这里做的
That's all that this does right here,
它会覆盖任何 CMD ，因此您可以构建容器
is it overrides whatever the CMD is,
so you can build containers
被设计用来过滤它们的指令对吧
that are designed to have commands
filtered into them, right?
这么说有道理吗 好的
So it make sense?
Okay, cool.
所以我要在这里说几个数字，对吧 ?
So it's annoying that I have
to say number here, right?
就好像有名字就好了，所以
Like it'd be better if there
was like name for it, so
那就这么做吧 Docker 建得好
let's do that, so docker build.
而这里的秩序非常重要
And again,
the order here is quite important,
我们要做的是标记我的节点应用程序
we're gonna do -- tag my-node app.
现在它就会是速成的库
Now it's gonna be instant cuz
it's the exact same Dockerfile so
一切都已经存在了
everything already exists.
还在为你缓存这些层对吧
It still is caching all those layers for
you, right?
所以它没有重做同样的事情。
So it doesn't redo the same thing.
现在我有了我的应用程序 : 最新的，
And so now I have my-node-app: latest,
它会自动把标签放在我们的上面
which it automatically puts
that tag on there for us.
这些都是有效的
That it all just works.
>> 是否要指定版本号，还是始终是最新的 ?
&gt;&gt; Do we have to specify the version
number or is it always gonna be latest?
>> 如果未指定，
&gt;&gt; If you don't specify it,
如果您指定了它，那么它将为您提供最新的信息。
It will give you latest,
if you do specify it then it wiil.
> > 是否有很好的做法 ?
&gt;&gt; Is there a good practice for that?
>> 您应该对容器进行版本处理。
&gt;&gt; You should version your containers,
yeah.
但你可以看到标签是西方的，对吧 ?
But as you can see tags are the wild west,
right?
你可以为所欲为
You can name them whatever you want and
就像很多人都有不同的策略
like lots people have
various different strategies.
但我想关键是
But I guess the key there is,
我们只是想知道人们在做什么对吧
we just wanna be obvious about
what people are getting, right?
他们就是这么想的
That's what they expect.
那么，我们现在还是做这个，好，就是给你看，
So, let's actually even do that right now,
well, just to show you,
Docker 运行 my-node-app ，现在就行了吗 ?
docker run my-node-app,
This now works right?
但让我们说我又这么做了我们要建造它
But let's say I did this again and
we're gonna build it and
我要放 1 号好吗
I'm gonna put :1, right?
这是标记，然后我成功将它标记为我的节点应用程序 : 1.
So this is the tag, then I successfully
tag this as my-node-app:1.
现在让我们改变这一点
Now let's go change this, so it says,
让我们回到罗夫湖因为那也很有启发性
let's go back to rofl because
that was enlightening as well.
根据布莱恩的理论，我们将把它放在那里，而不是 1个。
Philosophy according to Brian, and we're
going to put in there 2 now instead of 1.
所以现在我可以进来说 docker 运行了我的应用程序 : 1，
So now I can come in here and
say docker run my-node-app: 1,
如果我 2 岁我就会得到我的长袍
and I'll get omg hi lol and
if I do 2, I'll get rofl, so
这就像是最基本的 " intro-to-dockerfile " ，对吧 ?
that's like the most basic
intro-to-dockerfiles, right?
这显示了如何标记它们，如何构建它们，以及
That's showing you how to tag them,
how to build them, and
最基本的指令集对吧
the most basic set of instructions, right?
他们都有 FROM我们大多数人都要在我们的
All of them are gonna have a FROM,
most of us are going to be building our
自己的基本形象别问我怎么做我自己都没做过
own base images and don't ask me how to,
cuz I've never done it myself.
我没必要对吧
I've never needed to, right?
我从没想过建造自己的 Ubuntu
I've never needed to build my own Ubuntu.
讽刺的是我能更好地利用 Ubuntu
Canonical is much better
building Ubuntu that I am,
就像比我好多了那是个笑话
just like mildly better than I am,
that's, that's a joke,
Canonical 让 Ubuntu 我觉得他们比我强多了
Canonical makes Ubuntu I think
they're a lot better at it than I am.